In this video, I'd like to
在这段视频中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
show you a fun and historically
我想向你介绍一个具有历史意义的
important example of Neural Network Learning.
神经网络学习的重要例子
Of using a Neural Network for autonomous driving
那就是使用神经网络来实现自动驾驶
that is getting a car to learn to drive itself.
也就是说使汽车通过学习来自己驾驶
The video that I
接下来我将演示的
showed a minute, was something
这段视频
that I've gotten from Dean Pomilieu,
是我从 Dean Pomerleau那里拿到的
who Colleague who works
他是我的同事
out in Carnegie Mellon University out
任职于美国东海岸的
on the east coast of the United States,
卡耐基梅隆大学
and in part of the
在这部分视频中
video you see visualizations like
你就会明白可视化技术到底是什么
this, and what I should tell you what the visualization
在看这段视频之前
looks like before starting to
我会告诉你可视化技术是什么
video. Down here
在下面
on the lower left is the
也就是左下方
view seen by the car
就是汽车所看到的
of what's in front of it
前方的路况图像
and so here you know, you will kind
在图中你依稀能看出
of see you know, a road that's
一条道路
maybe going a bit to
朝左延伸了一点
the left and going a little bit to
又向右了一点
the right, and up
然后上面的这幅图
here on top, this
你可以看到一条
first horizontal bar shows the
水平的菜单栏
direction selected by the
显示的是驾驶操作人
human driver and is the
所选择的方向
location of this bright
就是这里的
white band that shows the
这条白亮的区段
steering direction selected by the
显示的就是
human driver, where, you
人类驾驶者选择的方向
know, here, far to the left
比如 最左边的区段
corresponds to steering hard left;
对应的操作就是向左急转
here corresponds to steering hard
而最右端则对应
to the right; and so
向右急转的操作
this location, which is a
因此 稍微靠左的区段
little bit to the left,
也就是这里
a little bit left of
中心稍微向左一点的位置
center, means that the human
则表示在这一点上
driver, at this point, was
人类驾驶者的操作是
steering slightly to the left.  A
慢慢的向左拐
nd this second part here
这幅图的第二部分
corresponds to the steering
对应的就是
direction selected by the
学习算法选出的行驶方向
learning algorithm; and again, the
并且 类似的
location of this sort
这一条白亮的区段
of white band, means the
显示的就是
neural network was here, selecting
神经网络在这里
a steering direction just slightly to
选择的行驶方向
the left and in fact,
是稍微的左转 并且实际上
before the neural network starts
在神经网络开始
learning initially, you
学习之前
see that the network outputs a
你会看到网络的输出是
grey band, like a
一条灰色的区段
grey uniform, grey band throughout
就像这样的一条灰色区段
this region, so the uniform
覆盖着整个区域  这些均称的
grey fuzz corresponds to the
灰色区域显示出
neural network having been randomly
神经网络已经随机初始化了
initialized, and initially having
并且初始化时
no idea how to
我们并不知道 汽车如何行驶
drive the car, or initially having
或者说
no idea what direction to steer in.
我们并不知道所选行驶方向
And it's only after it's learned
只有在学习算法运行了
for a while that it will then start
足够长的时间之后
to output like a solid white
才会有这条白色的区段
band in just a small
出现在整条灰色区域之中
part of the region corresponding
显示出一个具体的
to choosing a particular steering direction.
行驶方向
And that corresponds to when a neural network.
这就表示神经网络算法
Becomes more confident in selecting, you know,
在这时候已经选出了一个
a and in one
明确的行驶方向
location rather than outputting
不像刚开始的时候
a sort of light gray
输出一段模糊的浅灰色区域
fuzz, but instead outputting
而是输出
a white band that's
一条白亮的区段
more constantly selecting one steering direction.
表示已经选出了明确的行驶方向
Alban is a system
ALVINN (Autonomous Land Vehicle In a Neural Network)
of artificial neural networks, that learns to steer
是一个基于神经网络的智能系统
by watching a person drive. Alban
通过观察人类的驾驶来学习驾驶
is designed to control the
ALVINN能够控制NavLab载具——
tube a modified army
一辆改装版军用悍马
Humvee who could put
这辆悍马装载了
sensors, computers and actuators
传感器 计算机和驱动器
for autonomous navigation experiments.
用来进行自动驾驶的导航试验
The initial spec in
实现ALVINN功能的第一步
configuring Alban is training in
是对它进行训练
the training the person drives
也就是训练一个人驾驶汽车
to be a car while Alban watches.
然后让ALVINN观看
Once every two seconds, Alban
ALVINN每两秒
digitizes a video image
将前方的路况图生成一张数字化图片
of the road ahead, and records the person's steering direction.
并且记录驾驶者的驾驶方向
This training image is reduced
得到的训练集图片
in resolution to 30 by
被压缩为30x32像素
32 pixels and provided
并且作为输入
as input to Alban's three-layer
提供给ALVINN的三层
network.
神经网络
Using the back propagation learning algorithm; Alban
通过使用反向传播学习算法
is training to output the same
ALVINN会训练得到一个
steering direction as the
与人类驾驶员操纵方向
human driver for that image
基本相近的结果
Initially, the network's steering response is random.
一开始 我们的网络选择出的方向是随机的
After about two minutes of
大约经过两分钟的训练后
training, the network learns
我们的神经网络
to accurately imitate the steering
便能够准确地模拟
reactions of the
人类驾驶者的
human driver. This same
驾驶方向
training procedure is repeated for other road types.
对其他道路类型 也重复进行这个训练过程
After the networks have been trained the
当网络被训练完成后
operator pushes the run
操作者就可按下运行按钮
switch and often begins
车辆便开始行驶
driving. 12 times
每秒钟ALVINN生成
per second, Alban digitizes an
12次数字化图片
image and feeds it to its neural networks.
并且将图像传送给神经网络进行训练
Each network, running in parallel,
多个神经网络同时工作
produces a steering direction and a measure of it's
每一个网络都生成一个行驶方向
confidence in its response.
以及一个预测自信度的参数
The steering direction
预测自信度最高的
from the most confident network.
那个神经网络得到的行驶方向
In this case, the network trained
比如这里 在这条单行道上训练出的网络
for the one-lane road is used to control the vehicle.
将被最终用于控制车辆方向
Suddenly, an intersection appears ahead
车辆前方突然出现了
of the vehicle.
一个交叉十字路口
As the vehicle approaches the intersection,
当车辆到达这个十字路口时
the confidence of the one-lane network decreases.
我们单行道网络对应的自信度骤减
As it crosses the intersection, and
当它穿过这个十字路口时
the two-lane road ahead comes
前方的双车道将进入其视线
into view, the confidence of the two-lane network rises.
双车道网络的自信度便开始上升
When it's confidence rises, the two-lane
当它的自信度上升时 双车道的网络
network is selected to steer,
将被选择来控制行驶方向
safely guiding the vehicle
车辆将被安全地引导
into it's lane, on the two-lane road.
进入双车道路
So that was autonomous
这就是基于神经网络的
driving using a neural network. Of course, there are more
自动驾驶技术 当然 我们还有很多
recently more modern attempts
更加先进的试验
to do autonomous driving in a few properties, in
来实现自动驾驶技术
the U.S., in Europe, and so on.
在美国 欧洲等一些国家和地区
They're giving more robust driving
他们提供了一些比这个方法
controllers than this, but I
更加稳定的驾驶控制技术
think it's still pretty remarkable and
但我认为 使用这样一个简单的
pretty amazing how a simple
基于反向传播的神经网络
neural network trained with back-propagation
训练出如此强大的自动驾驶汽车
can, you know, actually learn to drive a car somewhat well.
的确是一次令人惊讶的成就